

📞 +57 3218477149

# Nicolás Rubio García

## Data analyst

## **ABOUT**

Certified data analyst, Political Science and Economics student, and enthusiast of web programming. About to graduate as a political scientist, and looking forward to a Master's in Data Science. I have authored articles and participated as a speaker at national congresses, with experience in the development and management of research projects, as well as in the analysis and modeling of massive datasets.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Data Analyst Consultant**

Corporación Programa Desarrollo para la Paz del Magdalena Centro, December 2023 - December 2023

- Collaboration in the design and implementation of the comprehensive monitoring and evaluation system for the Corporation.
- · Generation of accurate and relevant statistical inputs for the Management Report corresponding to the year 2023.
- Creation of detailed maps for regional characterization.

#### Freelance Data Analyst

Freelance, March 2023 - Present

- Development of an innovative methodology to measure the performance of healthcare systems in Latin America.
- Analysis and modeling of data extracted from the GEIH 2022-2023.
- · Detailed characterization of various indicators to drive regional development in Magdalena Centro.

#### Political Science Intern - Data Analyst

Corporación Programa Desarrollo para la Paz del Magdalena Centro, June 2023 - December 2023

- Comprehensive diagnosis and update of databases.
- · Thorough analysis and detailed evaluation of data.
- · Creation of executive reports synthesizing and effectively communicating findings.
- Development of specialized documents for municipal characterization.

## LANGUAGES



## PORTFOLIO AND NETWORKS



## **CERTIFICATION**

Google Advanced Data Analytics Professional Certificate, 2024

Data Science and Artificial Intelligence Certificate, 2023

Data cleaning and preprocessing - Outstanding,

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor's Degree in Political Science, 2019 - 2023 (Awaiting the graduation ceremony).

Bachelor's Degree in Economics, 2021 - Present.

Science and Artificial Intelligence Bootcamp, 2023 - Present.

Diploma in Programming Skills with Emphasis on Websites, 2022.

Diploma in Applied Statistics and Applied Econometrics, 2023

## **SKILLS**

Hard	Soft
R	Problem solving
Python	Teamwork
MySQL	Communication
Power BI	Active listening
Statistics	Critical thinking
Econometrics	Critical tilliking
Research	